<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on brig</title>
    <link>https://sahib.github.io/public/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on brig</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 14:09:01 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sahib.github.io/public/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is it?</title>
      <link>https://sahib.github.io/public/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 14:09:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sahib.github.io/public/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>»brig« is a free, distributred and quite secure file synchronization program. It is based on the global peer-to-peer filesystem ipfs. Think of it as »git« for big files focused on syn
It tries to focus on being up conceptually simple, by hiding a lot of complicated details regarding storage and security. Therefore I hope the end result is easy and pleasant to use, while being to be secure by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://sahib.github.io/public/post/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 14:07:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sahib.github.io/public/post/resume/</guid>
      <description>Encryption of data in rest and transport + compression on the fly. Simplified git version control (no real branches). Sync algorithm that can handle moved files and empty directories and files. Your data does not need to be stored on the device you are using. FUSE filesystem that feels like a normal (sync) folder. No central server at all. Still, central architectures can be build with brig. Simple user management with users that look like email addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help out!</title>
      <link>https://sahib.github.io/public/post/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 14:08:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sahib.github.io/public/post/projects/</guid>
      <description>»brig« is currently developed by a single guy in his spare time. While he&amp;rsquo;s pretty stubborn, you can probably guess that he could probably need some help. In it&amp;rsquo;s current state, the software is still far away from being production ready. This is partly due to missing testing, partly due to many bugs that are present in the software. Also, the security related code needs review before serious use in the wild.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>